ORIGINAL STORY WEBTOON SWEET HOME
BY CARNBY KIM AND YOUNGCHAN HWANG
SWEET HOME
DAY 337 OF THE MONSTERIZATION OUTBREAK
Five minutes until roll call.
Please pause your current engagements
and return to your positions.
Five minutes until roll call.
Please prepare for the roll call
in your living area.
Please check for any missing persons
and wait in your positions.
Wait for me.
Additionally, survivors will not
participate in this expedition.
Survivors' expeditions
are forbidden for the time being.
This decision was made
to ensure your safety.
Please trust the Platoon's decision
and cooperate with us.
Please check for any missing persons.
Over.
Give it back!
Give it to me!
When did he get this scar?
Last night.
This could be a problem.
It doesn't look concerning.
Don't get all soft, you idiot.
We gotta be sure.
Come on, don't do this.
He's just a kid.
Kids turn into monsters too.
There are no exceptions.
I'll do it then.
You should've done it last night.
You can check me first.
Happy?
We should be extra thorough with you.
It's only fair for a murderer, isn't it?
Sir.
I think that's enough.
Here.
Is this good enough?
Let's go.
Are you all right, ma'am?
My stomach hurts.
Would you like some aspirin?
You sure I can have it?
But I have no way to repay you.
Thank you so much.
Don't mention it.
Ma'am, where's your son?
Is he not out there?
Wait a minute.
Oh Jun-il, number 211, unaffiliated,
is missing in Area A.
Hey.
How did you get up here again?
What about the roll call?
Take me with you.
I want to come.
To do what?
To die?
No, to…
To kill.
Sure, we need to kill monsters.
But you haven't even
served in the military.
Do you even have a gun?
No.
Maybe you couldn't go
because you didn't have one.
Didn't your mom buy you a gun?
Come on, Sarge.
Give him a break.
Don't make fun of me, you fucker!
I'll kill you!
That's enough.
What a nuisance.
What's going on?
Sir.
Having a picnic?
Come on, Kim.
We were just letting loose.
Well, you better not.
We're heading into
an unverified area today.
-This isn't your usual expedition.
-Let's go.
We don't know what to expect. Understood?
-Yes, sir.
Be ready to leave in five minutes.
Is it even that dangerous?
Or do you just pretend to search
and take all the loot for yourselves?
What the hell did you say?
-Listen!
-I just don't get it.
You used to take
as many survivors as you could.
So why are we banned now?
You even turned a blind eye
to the murder out there.
It's just hard to believe
that you're looking out for us!
Take it. It's dangerous out there.
Can we really go?
Isn't that what you wanted?
Yeah.
Of course it is.
Good luck then.
-Sorry?
-What?
Aren't you supposed to protect us--
"Supposed to"?
No, Sarge. I meant…
We have no obligation
to risk our lives for you.
Try to survive on your own out there.
It won't be long before you learn
not to take your life for granted.
Go on.
I won't stop you.
That son of a bitch!
He ain't shit without his gun!
Lower your voice. They'll hear you.
And what if they do?
They can't do anything about it.
But still…
You fucking coward.
Think of it this way.
The Crow Platoon
is basically our bodyguards.
-I got it.
-They're here to protect us.
What could they possibly do to us?
Come on, man.
Don't mind him.
Not everyone feels that way.
We're alive thanks to you.
Don't touch it.
It takes so long to heal.
Everyone goes through it.
I'm fine.
Don't worry.
I promise I'll get it today.
Are you seeing anyone, Sarge?
They pretend not to,
but everyone's seeing someone.
-Are you?
-Come on.
It wouldn't be right for me
to be dating when you're not.
I feel no need for it.
Are you saying you're single by choice?
I mean…
I've been thinking.
You're not bad-looking.
And you're good at
killing monsters and surviving.
You're a ten by today's standards, so why…
haven't you found anyone?
How's life treating you these days,
Seok-chan?
You always look so angry.
The boys are too scared to talk to you.
You should smile more.
Cut the nonsense.
How much ordnance do we have left?
We have enough grenades and explosives,
but we're low on ammo.
We got a box of incendiary
and three boxes of regular.
What about fuel?
If we don't find any,
this thing becomes junk.
Shouldn't you be more worried about that
than my love life?
Yes, sir.
Where were you?
How could you go there alone?
-That hurts.
-You fool!
-Stop it.
-How could you be so reckless?
-Please calm down.
-My goodness.
He came back.
You're 30.
You're not a little kid anymore.
You've got to start
behaving like a grown-up.
I can't take care of you forever.
Oh Jun-il.
You need to
get yourself together, all right?
Why do you keep going outside?
Medicine.
What?
You need medicine.
Every night,
you bite down to endure the pain.
You lost so many teeth
from biting down so hard.
I don't like it when you're sick, Mom.
I'll be going now.
He only went out because I was ill.
Please let it slide.
He may have missed the roll call,
but he's a good boy.
He doesn't have a bad bone in his body.
Don't worry about him.
I just couldn't hide it.
He grew up seeing me sick all his life.
Is it bad?
It's cancer.
Ever since last month,
my insides feel like
they're being ripped apart.
I must be relapsing.
If I were alone,
I would've died a long time ago.
But I was so worried about Jun-il
that I held on for dear life.
But I don't think I have much time left.
The thought of leaving
that boy alone in this world…
You said they'd let us out if we insisted.
I was hoping to fill my stomach for once.
But fat chance now.
You idiot.
Is that all you have to wish for?
So they thought we'd back out
if they scared us?
What are you going to do now?
Stop causing trouble.
Let's go.
Where to?
To the person
that even the soldiers can't look down on.
Are you there, Chief Ji?
Chief Ji.
It's me, Do Sang-jin.
Hello, how have you been?
I told you not to come here.
It's a bit urgent.
What is it?
I can't stand not going on expeditions.
So what do you want me to do?
Please help us.
I know you're not a fan
of the Platoon either.
When we got bombarded,
you and Gi-nam were the ones
that led the people here.
But those assholes
act like they own the place.
They even turned a blind eye to
what happened to Gi-nam.
I'm sorry.
My tongue slipped.
If you're hungry, work.
There's work to do today.
But I want to go outside.
And do what?
I want to live a decent life.
I can't stand being stuck
underground like this.
Everyone else does.
Stop whining.
Come on, Chief.
Talk to them on behalf of the survivors.
The Platoon does their job and I do mine.
We agreed not to interfere.
But I could help you…
if you help me.
Sorry?
You want to go out, don't you?
PLEASE COOPERATE WITH THE MILITARY
TO RESTORE ORDER AND SAFETY
SHELTER ADMISSION PROTOCOL
Security deactivated.
All clear.
Open the gate. We're moving out.
BEER
FRENCH PHRASEBOOK
Sounds fucking ridiculous.
CURRY POWDER
What the hell are you doing?
Are you crazy?
Let me have some.
Let go, you crazy bitch.
Let go!
For fuck's sake.
Give it back.
Giving is giving, taking back is stealing.
Did you just cuss me out?
You totally did.
Are you even actually crazy?
You're pretending to be crazy
to leech off my mom, aren't you?
It's the pretty girl.
Pretty girls end up becoming monsters.
Where's Chief Ji?
Mom's out working. She's busy unlike you.
No one has more free time than you do.
Hey.
I didn't see any blonde-red ones
in your last batch.
They're all red.
No two shades of red are the same.
Go find it.
It's "blonde-red."
Was my dad's blood this shade of red,
or was it closer to this?
You crazy bitch!
Didn't you know?
I lost my shit a long time ago.
But I haven't totally lost it.
And I don't know what I'll do
when that happens.
So please…
watch your damn mouth.
Fuck this shit.
I'm out.
I'll double your 200 million.
Just fold if you're scared.
Are you even allowed to gamble?
Taking your sweet time with it,
aren't you?
Fine, I'm out.
Come on, just start the next round.
I had nothing.
You were bluffing?
That's amazing.
Don't give up until the end.
That's how you win in this world.
All right, one more game.
Hey.
This is an unverified area.
We shouldn't be here.
It's only unverified to us.
Chief Ji knows where everything is
and which paths lead where.
We were told to follow her,
so we're allowed to be here.
What's he doing here?
Should we take him with us?
Why would we?
We don't know what we might come across.
Slow down.
Yes, sir.
We're in the unverified area.
Move to our search point.
Get into position and scan the area.
We're in the operation area.
Start recon.
Sweep the area.
Hey, how's it looking?
Looks okay.
-Are we good?
-Yeah.
Did Chief Ji tell her about this path?
Why would she do that?
So she'll fuck off and die.
No way.
I doubt she was doing her a favor.
She killed her husband.
Well, that makes sense.
But she didn't tell us anything.
How does she want us to help her?
She said she keeps going out alone
and coming back alive.
She told us about this safe path
so we could snoop on her.
You got it?
Jun-il, lead the way.
Huh?
I'm not allowed to go out alone.
But you're not alone.
We're coming with you.
You should find some food
for your mom to eat
while she still has teeth.
Don't you think so?
Hell yeah! Jackpot!
What is she doing?
Hey, she's moving.
Let's go back. We grabbed enough stuff.
We can just make stuff up about her.
Let's kill her.
What?
With her out of the picture,
this is all ours.
We were ordered to just watch her.
She'll be happy if we kill her.
Wait, I got it!
Chief Ji sent us out here to kill her!
What are you saying? She never said that.
She doesn't have to say it out loud.
Read between the lines.
You're driving me crazy.
I have a gun now.
-My gun.
-Give me that.
Where did you find this?
Stay alert.
Hold your fire.
Alpha, classify it.
The rest of you, be ready to open fire.
Type Green.
Let's just get rid of it.
We're low on gas.
It's an unnecessary fight.
Fine.
What's wrong with that thing?
It looks disgusting.
Don't say that, sir.
It's crying.
"It's crying"?
Hey.
Those things don't cry.
They just make noises.
Does it look like it's crying?
Not to me, it doesn't.
What's going on?
Is that your girlfriend?
What are you talking about, sir?
It's into bald guys.
But if we're in its territory,
we should be fine, right?
This is good then.
Take your girl over there
and stay out of the way.
She's being a nuisance.
What will I do with it?
What's that?
Go to the playground.
Put a ring on its finger
and take the day off.
I heard we're repairing the outer wall.
It sounds dangerous.
The Platoon's coming with us.
And we were fine last time.
Well, it's definitely better
than going on expeditions.
It's safe,
but we don't get much out of it.
They don't even give us that much ration.
Those expeditions were pretty sweet.
We'd even find booze from time to time.
Damn it, now I want to drink.
Where are we going today?
Are you seriously here for work?
A man's gotta eat.
He can't be serious.
He must be out of gambling money.
Have some decency.
Why would Chief Ji take you?
Exactly.
Stop mucking up the waters in here.
Just get lost.
Why should I?
What the hell did I do wrong?
Are you serious?
You're that witch's family.
What are you…
My family name is Kang!
I don't share a single drop of blood
with Lee Eun-yu!
When you really hate someone,
you even hate their dog.
You people are only alive
because of Chief Ji's generosity.
You should've been kicked out
a long time ago, you know that?
-Damn it!
-What are you going to do?
Nothing.
-Just let it go.
-You little…
Damn it.
Ms. Jung.
Could you talk to Chief Ji
so I can go out and work today?
Why do you keep asking me?
Everything they said was true.
Well, it just feels unfair.
You can blame Lee Eun-yu.
It's all that crazy bitch's fault.
-Hello!
-Hello.
Mom!
-Mom.
-Hello.
How's your back?
It's fine, thanks to you.
-Are you feeling okay?
-Yes.
Hello, everyone.
Today, we'll be repairing
the east side of the outer wall.
It's outside work,
so please understand
that only a few can go.
-Mr. Yoon.
-Yes?
-Where's Cheol-yong?
-Here.
-Mr. Kim.
-Thank you.
No problem. Jae-chan.
-Seok-chan.
-Thank you.
-Skinny!
-Here!
And lastly…
Seung-wan.
Yes?
Yes, ma'am!
Let's get it done before sundown.
-Let's go.
-Yes, ma'am.
The rest of you, get on with your days.
Go on.
She's too generous.
Might as well call her Chief Buddha.
Why would she take that bastard?
Hey, watch your mouth.
She's the one who keeps this place
up and running.
I'm just disappointed she didn't pick me
even with a big heart over my head.
Come on.
Come to the testimony meeting today.
Come and hear the good word.
Thank you.
Let your troubles off your hearts.
You can have some if you come.
Ease your pain.
And fulfill your duties.
What a waste of your pretty face.
Don't you think so, Jin-a?
Go over there.
SUNGIL UNIVERSITY HOSPITAL
Chief Ji.
Is there any way I could join you?
It's tough work.
That's fine.
I used to work
my whole farm all on my own.
I'm sorry.
I know there are rewards
for working outside.
I can't always be a burden.
And I want to get some fresh air.
I could use some exercise. Please?
I'll just take
half of what the younger people get.
That's not the issue here.
Those are all mine.
Seon-hwa.
You see the apartment buildings
next to that building?
Those are all mine.
I'm so much richer than you are.
No.
Those are all mine too.
Then you should give me one
since I'm taking care of you.
Why should I?
You think I'm stupid?
Well, come sit here then.
He's always been an eye candy.
Look how pretty he is.
-Are you okay?
-I'm fine.
Oh, my.
Look at his smile.
He's irresistible.
Sounds like you're in love.
What?
Follow your heart.
So you won't have any regrets.
I know.
That's why I'm giving myself a makeover.
I need sunlight all over it.
I can't ask him out with splotchy hair.
Runner!
We got a runner!
Where's that idiot going?
I wish I could just shoot that moron.
-What about him?
-Whatever, just leave him.
Fucking bitch!
Fuck!
That little bitch.
Hey, Chan-yeong!
Chan-yeong!
Mom!
What the hell?
No!
Watch your feet!
Don't lift your foot.
Stay calm.
Why did you come all the way out here?
I wanted to disappear.
I wanted to go quietly,
but I guess I was asking for too much.
I thought I'd learned to accept death,
but I was wrong.
I'm scared.
I think I want to live.
Even in my old age…
After all those years…
I guess I still want to live.
I can't stand like this for much longer.
Step back.
Don't get yourselves hurt
because of a worthless old woman.
I'm a nuisance until the moment I die.
Don't come here!
Give me your hand.
Do you know how to defuse it?
No.
Just stay still.
Help will arrive soon.
You shouldn't sleep here.
Hey.
Wake up.
Medicine.
I don't like it when you're sick, Mom.
Mom?
I didn't do that.
Mom…
Mom is sick.
This isn't my fault.
It's all your fault.
Something must have gone wrong out there.
No, we should just go back in.
What the hell?
-What's going on?
-Let's wrap it up for today.
-Everybody, get inside.
-Listen to her.
Move! Chan-yeong!
-What are you going to do?
-Bring him back.
There's nothing we can do. Get inside.
So you want to just leave him?
Everybody, get back in.
Let go!
Let go of me!
Come back, Chan-yeong!
Hey!
You should go now.
I can't do that.
I have a favor to ask.
I haven't said goodbye to Jun-il.
If I die like this,
he'll think I abandoned him.
Tell him that's not the case.
Please tell him I didn't abandon him.
Tell him yourself.
You have to tell him that yourself.
How long has it been?
I'm not sure.
Step aside.
With all due respect,
I can't do that, sir.
She's only alive
because she's not a monster yet.
The mine should've exploded,
but it's most likely a dud.
Will she be all right then?
I'm just saying it's a possibility.
You'll lose your hand
if you keep holding on.
Let go of her.
It could still go off when she steps off.
And we don't know
its exact range of explosion.
We should still do everything we can, sir.
You could die if things go wrong.
So you're saying things could go right.
Come on, let's go back now.
Come out, come out, wherever you are
Please, let's just go back!
Little girl.
Come out, come out, wherever you are
Let's just go back!
For fuck's sake.
Shut up, you useless idiot.
Let's just go.
Please?
Hey.
It's just a kid.
Exactly.
What a relief.
Crazy bastard.
Hey.
Are you okay?
You're not dead, are you?
Hey, kid.
She's got human eyes.
Hey.
Leave.
You useless piece of shit.
Have you lost your fucking mind?
I'm a monster.
Get lost, you bastard.
Okay.
Bye then.
Damn it!
These are all mine.
No one else can have these.
I'm going to kill you all!
That's right.
No one can touch my stuff.
I wanna go…
What the hell?
Not a great haul today.
Aside from some tricky explosives,
it's all useless.
Someone must have swept this area already.
I'm glad there are
more survivors out here,
but I'm pissed that they beat us to it.
Hey, Kim.
Let's search another area.
We'll beat them this time.
No, it's raining.
We'll head back for now.
Sergeant Kim!
Staff Sergeant Choi has disappeared.
What are you talking about?
What about his comms?
He's not responding.
His radio is off.
Who saw Yong-seok last?
I saw him going to search the mall.
The area is too big
for us to search for him.
So what?
You want to leave him out here?
Would you say that if he was your family?
We're all family here, sir.
So why are you talking
like you don't give a shit?
Let's get you up.
Did that come from the shelter?
You think something's going on?
Kang Seok-chan.
Yes, sir.
Did you see blood
or signs of struggle at the mall?
No, sir.
Then we'll return.
-What about Yong-seok?
-The stadium comes first.
Most of the ordnance is with us.
We need to go back.
If Yong-seok isn't hurt,
he can make it back alone.
Or we can come back for him.
We need to go.
Come on.
-We're heading back.
-Prepare to head back!
Eun-hyeok.
It's you, isn't it?
It was you last time too.
I'm sure of it.
Eun-hyeok.
Eun-hyeok!
Can you show yourself just once?
Stop running away.
Please just let me see you.
I don't care what you look like,
so please let me see you.
Eun-hyeok.
I'm begging you.
Please show yourself just once.
Please…
Subtitle translation by Ji-hun Lee
Modify by Blue-Bird™